A Finding Aid to the Lee Nordness business records and papers, circa 1931-1992 (bulk 1954-1984), in the Archives of American Art AAA.nordlee
Archives of American Art
- Forms & Objects, Inc., circa 1959-1984; circa 1931; Series 3; 13.5 Linear feet Boxes 93-106, 120
  - Correspondence, circa 1959-1984; 3.1
    - Koblick, Freda, 1967-1972 (Box 95, Folder 26)
    - Kottler, Howard, 1968-1974; 1980 (Box 95, Folder 27)
    - "L" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1968-1977 (Box 95, Folder 28-29)
    - La Verdiere, Bruno, 1968-1980 (Box 95, Folder 30-31)
    - Lasser, Phyllis A., 1968-1970 (Box 95, Folder 32)
    - Lechtzin, Stanley, 1968-1973 (Box 95, Folder 33)
    - Lewis, John, circa 1973-1974 (Box 95, Folder 34)
    - Lipofsky, Marvin, 1968-1975 (Box 95, Folder 35)
    - Lipski, Donald, 1972-1973 (Box 95, Folder 36)
    - Littleton, Harvey, 1967-1974 (Box 95, Folder 37-39)
    - Loeber, Ken, 1978 (Box 95, Folder 40)
    - Lovato, Charles, 1972 (Box 95, Folder 41)
    - "M" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1968-1984 (Box 95, Folder 42)
    - "M-O" Miscellaneous, 1968-1982 (Box 95, Folder 43)
    - Maloof, Sam, 1968-1969 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Marshall, John [catalogs], 1967-circa 1973 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - McCormick, Patrick, 1968-1974 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Interoffice Memos, 1968-circa 1969 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Munick, Leo, MD, 1970-1971 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Museum of Contemporary Crafts, 1968-1972 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Museum of Modern Art, circa 1968-1971 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Museums, 1974-1978 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Museums, Galleries, Colleges, Etc., 1968-1974 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Myers, Joel Philip, 1968-1975 (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - "N" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1969-1984 (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - National Art and Antiques Festival, 1970; 1968 (Box 96, Folder 13)
    - Natzler, Gertrud and Otto, 1968-1971 (Box 96, Folder 14)
    - Nelson, Paul, 1971-1972 (Box 96, Folder 15)
    - Neumann, William A., 1972-1974 (Box 96, Folder 16)
    - "No" File (1969 August - 1971 November), 1968-1972 (Box 96, Folder 17)
    - No-Nos, 1973-1976 (Box 96, Folder 18)
    - Nomura, Ruth, 1976 (Box 96, Folder 19)
    - Northwest Craft Center and Gallery, 1968-1982 (Box 96, Folder 20)
    - "O" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1968-1975 (Box 96, Folder 21)
    - Öhrström, Edvin, 1968; 1974; 1979 (Box 96, Folder 22)
    - Ownership,Certificate of, 1969 (Box 96, Folder 23)
    - "P" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1968-1980 (Box 96, Folder 24)
    - "P-R" Miscellaneous, 1968-1984 (Box 96, Folder 25)
    - Parrott, Alice Kagawa, 1968-1970 (Box 96, Folder 26)
    - Perimeter Press, Jack Earl Book Contract, 1980 (Box 96, Folder 27)
    - Photograph Reorders, 1969 (Box 96, Folder 28)
    - Photos, Forms & Objects Works, 1968-1970s (Box 96, Folder 29)
    - Posner, Richard, 1982 (Box 96, Folder 30)
    - Prip, John, 1968-1973 (Box 96, Folder 31)
    - Project Relief, Inc., 1972 (Box 96, Folder 32)
    - Projects, New, 1969 (Box 96, Folder 33)
    - Publicity, Magazines and Newspapers, 1968-1970 (Box 96, Folder 34)
    - "R" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1968-1978 (Box 96, Folder 35)
    - Rabinovich, Raquel, circa 1974 (Box 96, Folder 36)
    - Radakovich, Ruth and Toza, 1968-1971 (Box 96, Folder 37)
    - Randall, Douglas, 1970-1971 (Box 96, Folder 38)
    - Renk, Merry, 1968-1974 (Box 96, Folder 39)
    - Renwick Gallery, 1971 (Box 96, Folder 40)
    - Requests, Collectors and Photos, 1968-1975 (Box 96, Folder 41)
    - Restorations, circa 1970s (Box 96, Folder 42)
    - Richmond, Colin, 1968-1969 (Box 96, Folder 43)
    - Rose, Mildred, Burglery, 1970-1979 (Box 96, Folder 44)
    - Rossbach, Ed, 1968-1977 (Box 96, Folder 45-46)
    - Sauer, Dick, 1975; 1979 (Box 96, Folder 47)
    - Schwarcz, June, 1968-1970 (Box 96, Folder 48)
    - "S" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1968-1982 (Box 96, Folder 49)
    - "S-U" Miscellaneous, 1968-1975 (Box 96, Folder 50)
    - Security National (77th and 3rd Ave.), 1968-1973 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Sekimachi, Kay, 1968-1973 (Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Shaw, Richard, 1969-1975 (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Shows in Gallery, circa 1968-1969 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - Shows Out of Gallery, Pending, 1974 (Box 97, Folder 5)
    - Shows Out of Gallery, Returned, 1968-1971 (Box 97, Folder 6)
    - Standard Conditions for Touring Shows, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 7)
    - Slides, 1971-1972 (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Sloane, Carol, 1971-1974 (Box 97, Folder 9)
    - Smith, Paul, 1973-1977 (Box 97, Folder 10)
    - Soldner, Paul, 1968-1975 (Box 97, Folder 11-12)
    - Soleri, Paulo, 1969-1973 (Box 97, Folder 13)
    - Sperry, Robert, 1968-1969 (Box 97, Folder 14)
    - Stewart, Bill, 1970-1974 (Box 97, Folder 15-16)
    - Supplies, 1968 (Box 97, Folder 17)
    - "T" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1968-1977 (Box 97, Folder 18)
    - Tanner, James, 1983; 1981 (Box 97, Folder 19)
    - Tasha, Carl, 1976 (Box 97, Folder 20)
    - Tours, European, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 21)
    - Tucker, Yvonne, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 22)
    - Underhill, William, 1969 (Box 97, Folder 23)
    - "V" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1971-1973 (Box 97, Folder 24)
    - "V-W" Miscellaneous, 1969-1977 (Box 97, Folder 25)
    - Viking Book Orders, 1970-1972 (Box 97, Folder 26)
    - Voulkos, Peter, 1968-1973 (Box 97, Folder 27)
    - "W" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1968-1979 (Box 97, Folder 28)
    - Wallace, Jerome, 1967-1974 (Box 97, Folder 29-32)
    - Westberg, Martial, circa 1969 (Box 97, Folder 33)
    - Westphal, Katherine, 1968-1971 (Box 97, Folder 34)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1974 (Box 97, Folder 35)
    - Wilhelmi, William, 1972-1977 (Box 97, Folder 36)
    - WIlson, Helen, 1972 (Box 97, Folder 37)
    - Wilson, Laurie J., 1974-1975 (Box 97, Folder 38)
    - Woell, J. Fred, 1968-1974 (Box 97, Folder 39)
    - Wyman, William, 1968-1971 (Box 97, Folder 40)
    - "X-Z" Miscellaneous Craftsmen, 1967-1974 (Box 97, Folder 41)
    - Yaruss, Daniel, 1973-1975 (Box 97, Folder 42)
    - Zachai, Dorian, 1968-1973 (Box 97, Folder 43)
    - Zelmanoff, Marci, 1971-1972 (Box 97, Folder 44)
    - Znamierowski, Nell, 1968-1973 (Box 97, Folder 45)
  - Lectures, 1971-1973; 3.2
    Lectures contains scripts for Lee Nordness' "Introspection" lectures given in numerous states from 1971-1973.
    Folders are arranged in rough chronological order based on the lecture date.
    - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 97, Folder 46)
    - ["Introspection"] (Midland, MI), 1971 (Box 97, Folder 47)
    - "Introspection" (Detroit, MI; March 27, 1972) (Box 97, Folder 48)
    - "Introspection '72" (Montgomery, AL), circa 1972 (Box 97, Folder 49)
    - "Introspection" (Detroit, MI and Montgomery, AL), 1972 (Box 97, Folder 50)
    - "Introspection '73", circa 1973 (Box 97, Folder 51)
    - "Introspection" (Genesea, NY), circa 1971-1973 (Box 98, Folder 1-2)
  - Public Relations Files, 1964-1971; 3.3
    This subseries contains press releases and artist's biographical information created by the public relations department of the gallery.
    - Arneson, Robert, 1969-1970 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Bailey, Clayton, 1965-1969 (Box 98, Folder 4)
    - Bauer, Fred and Patti, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 5)
    - Billeci, Andre, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Cartwright, Roy, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 7)
    - Castle, Wendell, 1969-1970 (Box 98, Folder 8)
    - Chihuly, Dale, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 9)
    - Christman, Anne Hornby, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 10)
    - Di Mare, Dominic, circa 1969 (Box 98, Folder 11)
    - Engle, Barbara, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 12)
    - Espenet, Arthur Carpenter, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 13)
    - Fabert, Jacques, 1968-1970 (Box 98, Folder 14)
    - Fisch, Arline, 1965-1971 (Box 98, Folder 15)
    - Guermonprez, Trude, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 16)
    - Halem, Henry and Judi, 1968-1969 (Box 98, Folder 17)
    - Hallman, Ted, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 18)
    - Heaton, Maurice, 1969; 1967 (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - Helwig, Harold Billy, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 20)
    - Horiuchi, Paul, 1968-1969 (Box 98, Folder 21)
    - Hui Ka-Kwong, 1968-1970 (Box 98, Folder 22)
    - Hultberg, Paul, 1964-1968 (Box 98, Folder 23)
    - Kaufman, Glen, 1968-1969; 1962 (Box 98, Folder 24)
    - Kington, Brent, 1968-1969 (Box 98, Folder 25)
    - Kottler, Howard, 1968-1969 (Box 98, Folder 26)
    - Kriegman, Carolyn, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 27)
    - La Verdiere, Bruno, 1965-1969 (Box 98, Folder 28)
    - Lasser, Phyllis, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 29)
    - Lechtzin, Stanley, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 30)
    - Lipofsky, Marvin, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 31)
    - Littleton, Harvey, 1966-1969 (Box 98, Folder 32)
    - Liu Kuo-sung, 1966-1970 (Box 98, Folder 33)
    - Maloof, Sam, 1966; 1968 (Box 98, Folder 34)
    - Mason, John, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 35)
    - McCormick, Patrick, circa 1969 (Box 98, Folder 36-37)
    - Michaels, Glen, circa 1968-1969 (Box 98, Folder 38)
    - Myers, Joel Philip, 1969-1970 (Box 98, Folder 39)
    - Natzler, Gertrud and Otto, circa 1964, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 40)
    - Parrott, Alice Kagawa, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 41)
    - Prip, John, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 42)
    - Radakovich, Ruth and Toza, 1966-1969 (Box 98, Folder 43)
    - Renk, Merry, 1968-1969 (Box 98, Folder 44)
    - Richmond, Colin, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 45)
    - Rossbach, Ed, 1968-1970 (Box 98, Folder 46)
    - Schwarcz, June, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 47)
    - Sekimachi, Kay, 1968-1970 (Box 98, Folder 48)
    - Soldner, Paul, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 49)
    - Sperry, Robert, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 50)
    - Underhill, William, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 51)
    - Wallace, Jerome, circa 1968-1970 (Box 98, Folder 52)
    - Westphal, Katherine, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 53)
    - Woell, J. Fred, 1968-1970 (Box 98, Folder 54)
    - Wolf, Jeanne, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 55)
    - Wyman, William, circa 1968 (Box 98, Folder 56)
    - Zachai, Dorian, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 57)
    - Znamierowski, Nell, 1968-1969 (Box 98, Folder 58)
    - Various Artists, 1968-1970 (Box 98, Folder 59)
  - Business Records, 1960s-1970s; 3.4
    This small subseries contains corporation records, forms, form letters, index cards for artist's addresses and collectors, and inventories.
    - Artist's Biographies, circa 1968-1970s (Box 98, Folder 60)
    - Corporate Records, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 61)
    - Filing Cabinet, Guarantee and Keys, circa 1968-1970s (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Form Letters, 1968-circa 1970 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    - Forms, Time Payment, circa 1968-1970s (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Index Cards: Artist's Addresses; Out of the Gallery; Collectors (shoebox), circa 1960s-1970s (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Inventory, 1970 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Inventory, Missing Works (June 1970), 1968-1970 (Box 99, Folder 6)
    - Inventory, Year End Figures, 1973 June (Box 99, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Financial and Sales Records, 1968-1983; 3.5
    Financial and Sales Records contains accounting ledgers, artist's statements, consignment sheets, paid bills and petty cash receipts, sales invoices, index cards for sold artwork, and tax records.
    - Accounting Ledger, Artists, circa 1968-1970s (Box 99, Folder 9)
    - Artist's Statements, 1968-1977 (Box 99, Folder 10-11)
    - Artist's Statements, Notes, circa 1968-1969 (Box 99, Folder 12)
    - Bank Statements, Chemical Bank, 1981-1983 (Box 99, Folder 13-14)
    - Cashbook, 1974-1981 (Box 99, Folder 15)
    - Cashbook, 1970-1974 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Commissions Due Artists, 1968-1973 (Box 100, Folder 2)
    - Commissions Paid, 1968-1970 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Commissions Payable, 1968-1970 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Consignment Sheets, 1968-1977 (Box 100, Folder 5-13)
    - Consignment Sheets, Arts/Objects, 1972-1973 (Box 100, Folder 14)
    - Paid Bills, 1968-1970 (Box 100, Folder 15-16)
    - Paid Bills, 1968-1970 (Box 101, Folder 1-4)
    - Paid Bills, 1969-1974 (Box 101, Folder 5-8)
    - Paid Bills, 1982-1983 (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Petty Cash and Expenses (1968-1970), 1974 (Box 101, Folder 10-12)
    - Petty Cash, 1970-1973 (Box 101, Folder 13-16)
    - Purchase Orders, 1968-1970 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Sales Invoices, 1968-1972 (Box 102, Folder 2-4)
    - Sales Invoices, Extra Copies, 1969-1972 (Box 102, Folder 5-6)
    - Sales Invoices, Master File, 1970-1973 (Box 102, Folder 7-8)
    - Sales Invoices, Objects:USA Sales, 1968-1969 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Shipping Receipts, 1968-circa 1971 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Sold Cards (2 shoeboxes), circa 1968-1974 (Box 102, Folder 11-12)
    - Tax Records, 1982-1983 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Tax Returns, 1979-1982 (Box 103, Folder 2-4)
    - Timecards, 1968-1970 (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Year End Figures, 1969-1982 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1960s-1970s; circa 1931; 3.6
    Found are artist's scrapbooks which contain a variety of materials such as black and white photographs of artwork with inventory number, date of painting, and other info; exhibition printed materials; press clippings; and slides. Also found is one folder containing a gallery publicity scrapbook.
    - Bailey, Clayton, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 7-8)
    - Castle, Wendell, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 9-10)
    - Fisch, Arline, 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 11-12)
    - Gallery Publicity, circa 1968-1969 (Box 103, Folder 13)
    - Hui Ka-Kwong, 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 14)
    - Lechtzin, Stanley, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 15-16)
    - Littleton, Harvey, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 103, Folder 17-19)
    - Littleton, Harvey, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 1-2)
    - Wallace, Jerome, circa 1931; 1960s-1971 (Box 104, Folder 3-6)
    - Wiener, Samuel, Jr., circa 1968-1970s (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Various Artists (Abend-Apodaca), 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Various Artists (Baptiste-Bauer), 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Various Artists (Bergia-Brynner), 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 10)
    - Various Artists (Cartwright-Dryenforth), 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 11)
    - Various Artists (Earl-Gilhooly), 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 12)
    - Various Artists (Gronberg-Guermonprez), 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 13)
    - Various Artists (Halem), 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 14)
    - Various Artists (Hallman-Hughto), 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 15)
    - Various Artists (Hultberg-Jessamin), 1960s-1970s (Box 104, Folder 16)
    - Various Artists (Kaufman-Kelly), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Various Artists (Kington-Koblick), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - Various Artists (Kottler-Lasser), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - Various Artists (Lavato-Lipofsky), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Various Artists (Lipofsky-Loloma), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - Various Artists (Long-Mason), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 6)
    - Various Artists (McCormick-Myers), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 7)
    - Various Artists (Natzler-Nichols), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - Various Artists (Parrott-Randall), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - Various Artists (Renk), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - Various Artists (Renk-Rossbach), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - Various Artists (Sanderson-Schwarcz), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - Various Artists (Sekimachi-Soldner), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - Various Artists (Soldner-Spinsky), 1960s-1970s (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - Various Artists (Stehman-Temple), 1960s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Various Artists (Thaler-Wallace), 1960s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Various Artists (Wallace-Widenhofer), 1960s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Various Artists (Wildenhain-Woell), 1960s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Various Artists (Woell-Wyman), 1960s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Various Artists (Yanagri-Znamierowski), 1960s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Materials, circa 1960s-1970s; 3.7
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
    Photographic Materials includes oversized photographs of jewelers and slides of artwork by various artists.
    - Photographs of Jewelers, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 106, Folder 7)
      Oversized material housed in Box 120, Folder 5
    - Slides From Various Artists, 1964-1971 (Box 106, Folder 8-10)
    - Oversized Photographs of Jewelers, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 120, Folder 5)
      Oversized material from Box 106, Folder 7
- American Art Expositions, Inc., 1955-1968; Series 4; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 106-107
  This series is arranged as 3 subseries:
  4.1: Art:USA:58, 1957-1958
  4.2: Art:USA:59, 1957-1962
  4.3 Business Records, 1955-1968
  The large-scale New York City contemporary art exhibitions organized by Lee Nordness, Art:USA:58 and Art:USA:59, are illustrated in the correspondence, banking records, founding documents, newspaper clippings, paid bill receipts, photographs of artists, and sales invoices of the American Art Expositions, Inc. records.
  - Art:USA:58, 1957-1958; 4.1
    The bulk of the materials found here are clippings and printed materials related to Art:USA:58. Also found is an address book for galleries, some correspondence, and paid bill receipts.
    - Address Book for Galleries, circa 1958 (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Clippings, 1957-1958 (Box 106, Folder 12-13)
    - Paid Bills, 1957-1958 (Box 106, Folder 14-17)
    - Paid Bills and Time Slips, 1957-1958 (Box 106, Folder 18)
    - Printed Materials, 1958 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Art:USA:59, 1957-1962; 4.2
    Art:USA:59 includes correspondence, publicity photographs of artists taken by photographer Fred Darrah, sales invoices, and a small clippings scrapbook.
    - Clippings, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box 107, Folder 3-4)
    - Craftsmen, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Insurance, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of Artists Taken by Fred Darrah, 1961-1962 (Box 107, Folder 7-9)
    - Public Relations, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - Sales Invoices, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 12)
    - Tickets, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 13)
  - Business Records, 1955-1968; 4.3
    Found are bank statements, founding documents, accounting index cards, meeting minutes, stock certificates, and tax records.
    - Bank Statements, Chemical Bank, 1959-1964 (Box 107, Folder 14-16)
    - Bank Statements, Morgan Guaranty Trust, 1960-1961 (Box 107, Folder 17)
    - Deposit Receipts, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 18)
    - Founding Documents and Meeting Minutes, 1958-1961 (Box 107, Folder 19)
    - Index Cards, Artists and Employees, 1955-1958 (Box 107, Folder 20)
    - Stock Certificates, circa 1958 (Box 107, Folder 21)
    - Tax Records, 1962-1968 (Box 107, Folder 22)
- The Little Studio, Inc., 1947-1969; Series 5; 7.7 Linear feet Boxes 108-115, 121
  The bulk of the records of The Little Studio, Inc. are financial records and sales invoices. Lee Nordness' involvement in the gallery is also documented through correspondence and business records.
  5.1: Correspondence, 1952-1963
  5.2: Business Records, 1947-1963
  5.3: Financial and Sales Records, 1952-1969
  - Correspondence, 1952-1963; 5.1
    Folders are arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by correspondent's last name.
    Correspondence is primarily in English, but some French and German. 1957 correspondence has some water damage and can be fragile.
    - General Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1952-1963 (Box 108, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence (1955 October - 1956 December), 1954-1957 (Box 108, Folder 2-13)
    - General Correspondence [1957], 1953-1958 (Box 108, Folder 14-24)
    - General Correspondence [1957], 1954-1959 (Box 109, Folder 1-12)
    - General Correspondence [1959], 1955-1961 (Box 109, Folder 13-32)
    - General Correspondence, Miscellaneous, circa 1959-1963 (Box 109, Folder 33)
    - Westhampton Gallery, 1961 (Box 109, Folder 34)
  - Business Records, 1947-1963; 5.2
    Business Records contains artist's biographies, two desk calendars, founding documents, guest books, inventory lists, a stamp, and other miscellaneous business records.
    - Address Book, circa 1955-1960s (Box 109, Folder 35)
    - Artist's Biographies, circa 1952-1963 (Box 109, Folder 36-37)
    - Artist's Biographies, 1947-circa 1963 (Box 110, Folder 1-4)
    - Brochure, 1950s (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Clippings and Printed Materials, circa 1952 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Desk Calendars (2 calendars), 1959-1960 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Founding Documents and Legal Records, 1952-1963 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Guest Books, 1958-1962 (Box 110, Folder 9-10)
      Oversized material housed in Box 121, Folder 1
    - Inventory, 1960s (Box 110, Folder 11)
    - Inventory, Ronald Julius Christensen, 1961-1962 (Box 110, Folder 12)
    - Lawyers Seals, circa 1952-1963 (Box 110, Folder 13)
    - [Lee Nordness's Notes], circa 1957 (Box 110, Folder 14)
    - Pepper Shaker, circa 1952-1963 (Box 110, Folder 15)
    - Shipping Labels and Forms, circa 1952-1963 (Box 110, Folder 16)
    - Stamp, circa 1952-1963 (Box 110, Folder 17)
    - Oversized Guest Book, 1958-1960 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      Oversized material from Box 110, Folder 9
  - Financial and Sales Records, 1952-1969; 5.3
    Financial and Sales Records contains accounting ledgers, banking records, paid bills receipts, sales invoices, sales ledgers, shipping records, and tax records.
    - Accounting Ledger, circa 1955-1963 (Box 110, Folder 18)
    - Accounting Ledger, 1959-1961 (Box 110, Folder 19)
    - Accounting Ledger, 1959-1961 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Accounting Ledger, 1960-1964 (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Approvals [Statements], 1959-1963 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Artist's Accounts, 1962-1963 (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Artist's General Releases and Commissions Payable, 1961; 1963 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Bank Passbook, 1959-1961 (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Bank Statements, 1965-1967 (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Bank Statements, The County Trust Co., 1963 (Box 111, Folder 8)
    - Bank Statements, Morgan Guaranty Trust, 1962-1965 (Box 111, Folder 9-12)
    - Banking, Miscellaneous, 1958-1965 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Bills and Receipts, 1958-1963 (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Cash Receipts and Disbursements Ledger, 1955-1958 (Box 111, Folder 15)
      Oversized material housed in Box 121, Folder 2
    - Check Stub Books (3 books), 1962-1966 (Box 111, Folder 16-18)
    - Delivery Book, Bill Wallace, 1957-1959 (Box 111, Folder 19)
    - Express In [Shipping Receipts], 1955-1958 (Box 111, Folder 20)
    - Financial Statements, 1952-1963 (Box 111, Folder 21)
    - Gimbels Statements, 1952-1956 (Box 112, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1959-1963 (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous [Bills and Correspondence - Gallery Closing?], 1957-1963 (Box 112, Folder 4-5)
    - Paid Bills, 1955-1956 (Box 112, Folder 6-8)
    - [Paid Bills], 1962-1963 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - [Petty Cash], 1964 (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - Sales Invoices, 1952-1953 (Box 112, Folder 11-12)
    - Sales Invoices, 1954-1956 (Box 113, Folder 1-3)
    - Sales Invoices (Boston), 1956-1957 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Sales Invoices (2nd Ave.), 1957 (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - Sales Invoices, 1957-1958; 1961-1963 (Box 114, Folder 1-6)
    - Sales Ledgers (3 ledgers), 1955-1960 (Box 114, Folder 7-9)
    - Shipping Receipts, 1958; 1960-1961 (Box 114, Folder 10-11)
    - Shipping Receipts, 1960-1963 (Box 115, Folder 1-2)
    - Stock Certificates and Ledger, 1955-1963 (Box 115, Folder 3)
    - Tax Records, 1955-1969 (Box 115, Folder 4-8)
    - Tax Records, New York, 1955-1963 (Box 115, Folder 9)
    - Trial Balance Ledgers (5 ledgers), 1953-1960 (Box 115, Folder 10-11)
    - Oversized Cash Receipts and Disbursements Ledger, 1955-1958 (Box 121, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 111, Folder 15
- Talent Discovery Company, 1953-1957; Series 6; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 115-116, 121